Name Antonio Kümin

Nationality Swiss and Brazilian

E-Mail tony@kumin.ch

#### **Personal Profile**

My interest in Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning started in my early teenager years by programming a chat-bot with which users could interact in a text-based role-playing-game. In my first year of university I learned the principles of AI and in the AI Lab (lead by Rolf Pfeifer). This was followed by seminars and other lectures where I designed a traffic simulation to analyze emerging behavior, and also where our team optimized the gait of our 3D printed quadruped robots.

For my Bachelor and Master theses and my time as research assistant I developed a debate structuring application and implemented an algorithm to analyze the structure of the pro/contra arguments, as well as using R to reduce dimensionality of the data, deduce and classify the relative opinions of the participants into groups for visualization. I worked intensively with my professor Lorenz Hilty of the Informatics & Sustainability lab on designing and validating his theory on debates.

# **Professional Experience**

10/2017 - present Adv. Analytics and Machine Learning Consultant, ipt Innovation Process Technology, Zurich, Switzerland Currently working on a mandate in Healthcare handling data to a database in Microsoft Azure cloud for customer insights

06/2015 - 09/2017 **Project Manager for securitized instruments and banking products**, UBS AG, Zurich, Switzerland Team Head and deputy Unit Head in the Product Inventory managing 10 employees in a delivery unit consisted of 30 full-time-equivalents working onshore and in a nearshore location.

Tasks include planning incoming change requests, understanding their business context, contributing to the impact analysis and estimating the change effort.

My responsibilities include oversight of the analysis, development and testing phases to ensure a successful deployment and acceptance of the delivery by the business representatives.

Throughout the RUP-based change project the team and I contribute towards identification, monitoring and mitigation of risks and to transparent communication to the stakeholders.

01/2014 - 05/2015 **Project Manager for commercial registry and investment funds**, UBS AG, Zurich, Switzerland Enhancements of strategic applications and a simultaneous enhancement and near-shoring of an application whereas my team and I were new to the subject matter.

07/2013 - 12/2013 Investment Specialist and Client Advisor Assistant in the front office, UBS AG, Zurich, Switzerland

09/2012 - 06/2013 IT Business Analyst in Legal IT, UBS AG, Zurich, Switzerland

2009 - 2012 Student Research Assistant in Data Science / Teaching Assistant, University of Zurich, Switzerland

2011 and 2012 Freelancer in Content Management System (Drupal) migration, Amazee Labs, Zurich, Switzerland

09/2011 - 01/2012 Digitalization project lead for requests towards IT department, MAN Diesel & Turbo, Zurich, Switzerland

06/2008 - 09/2008 Software Engineer (prototyping) for Software Asset Management, CIBA SC, Basel, Switzerland

### **Education**

09/2010 - 08/2012 Master of Science, University of Zurich, Switzerland – Magna cum laude

Degree in Business Information Systems. Thesis on the analysis of debates by means of classification

of opinions and dimensionality reduction.

09/2006 - 08/2010 Bachelor of Science, University of Zurich, Switzerland - Cum laude

Degree in Computer Science. Thesis on the CANDis research project for the implementation of a web application for collaboratively engaging on normative discourses (debates) and an algorithm for identifying the shortest course of actions for the users to reach a consensus in the debate.

# **Certifications and Courses**

10/2017	Neural Networks and Deep Learning by deeplearning.ai on Coursera
06/2017 - 09/2017	Machine Learning by Stanford University on Coursera
12/2016	Certified Project Management Professional (PMP), Project Management Institute
04/2009	Leadership development seminar at the Discovery '09 conference, AIESEC Switzerland
08/2006	First Certificate in English, University of Cambridge

# **Extracurricular Activities**

04/2012 - present Member of Rotaract, Zurich, Switzerland

Participating in social projects and organizing small events. Treasurer role from 2013/07 to 2015/06.

09/2011 - present Member of the voluntary fire brigade, Feuerwehr Kirü and Schutz & Rettung Zurich, Switzerland

04/2008 - 08/2012 Software Engineer CRM & Member database, AIESEC Swizerland

Working in External Relations on local and national level and in Talent Management on local level. Responsibilities include a Countrywide rollout and training of 60 users in the new CRM, assistance in organizing a conference for 350 members as well as design and implementation of the HR system

### Hard skills and Interests

Languages	German (native), Portuguese (native), English (fluent), Spanish (fluent), French (basic knowledge)
Processes	Scrum, Kanban, RUP/SDLC, Two finished startups in Trading Surveillance and Lawer Insurance spaces
Technologies	Oracle Data Integrator, HP Quality Center, Selenium, Serena Dimensions RM, Toad for Oracle, ServiceNow, JIRA, Confluence, Sharepoint/Nintex, MS Access, GIT
	Basic knowledge in MS Project, Photoshop, Informatica Powercenter, UNIX, Cloud PaaS (IBM Bluemix, Heroku), Cloud IaaS (Amazon Web Services), Watson Conversation
Programming	Javascript/Ajax/JQuery, Node.js, PHP, CSS/Bootstrap, HTML, SQL (MySQL, Oracle, MS SQL),
experience	NoSQL, Java, VBA, XPath/XQuery, Python
experience	NoSQL, Java, VBA, XPath/XQuery, Python  Basic knowledge in C / C++ (Processing), Drupal, MatLab, Octave and R
experience Interests	

# **Publications**

Master thesis Kümin, J. A. (2012), Evaluation of multivariate methods for dimensionality reduction and cluster

analysis in the context of a debate structuring system: http://www.merlin.uzh.ch/publication/show/7374

Bachelor thesis Kümin, J. A. (2010), Prototype of a WebApp for structuring and analysis of debates:

http://www.merlin.uzh.ch/publication/show/2415 (in German)